wonder by RJ palasio part seven Miranda!” I forgot that I might see so many beautiful things I
forgot that I might need to find out what life could bring andain beautiful things Camp
lies MY PARENTS GOT divorced the summer before 9th grade. My father was with
someone else right away. In fact, though my mother never said so, I think this was
the reason they got divorced. After the divorce, I hardly ever saw my father. And
my mother acted stranger than ever. It’s not that she was unstable or anything:
just distant. Remote. My mother is the kind of person who has a happy face for
the rest of the world but not a lot left
over for me. She’s never talk to me much—
—not about her feelings, her life. I don’t know much about what she was like when
she was my age. Don’t know much about the
things she liked or didn’t like. The few times she mentioned her own parents, who
I’ve never met, it was mostly about how she wanted to get as far away from them
as she could once she’d grown up. She never told me why. I asked a few times,
but she would pretend she hadn’t heard
me. I didn’t want to go to to camp that
summer. I had wanted to stay with her, to help her through the divorce. But she
insisted I go away. I figured she wanted the time alone so I gave it to her. Camp
was awful. I hated it. I thought it would be better being a junior counselor, but
it wasn’t. No one I knew from the previous year had come back, so I didn’t
know anyone— —not a single person. I’m not even sure why, but I started playing this
little make believe game with the girls in the camp. They’d ask me stuff about
myself, and I’d make things up: my parents
are in Europe, I told them. I live in a huge townhouse on the nicest street in
North River Heights. I have a dog named Daisy. Then one day I blurted out that I
had a little brother who was deformed. I have absolutely no idea why I said this:
it just seemed like an interesting thing to say. And, of course, the reaction I got
from the little girls in the bungalow was dramatic. Really? So sorry! That must
be tough etc etc I regretted saying this the moment it escaped from my lips, of
course: I felt like such a fake. If Via ever found out, I thought, she’d think I
was such a weirdo. And I felt like a weirdo. But, I have to admit, there was a
part of me that felt a little entitled to this lie. I’ve known Auggie since I
was 6 years old I I’ve watched him grow
up. I’ve played with him. I’ve watched all six episodes of Star Wars for his sake,
so I' talked to him about the aliens and bounty hunters and all that. I’m the one
that gave him the astronaut helmet he wouldn’t take off for 2 years. I mean,
I’ve kind of earned the right to think of him as my brother. And the strangest
thing is that these lies I told, these fictions, did wonders for my popularity.
The other junior counselors heard it from the campers, and they were all over
it. Never in my life have I ever been considered one of the “popular” girls in
anything, but that summer in camp, for whatever reason, I was the girl everybody
wanted to hang out with. Even the girls in bungalow 32 were totally into me
those were the girls at the top of the food chain. They said they liked my hair
(though they changed it). They said they like the way I did my makeup (though they
changed that, too). They showed me how to turn my T-shirts into halter tops. We
smoked. We snuck out late at night and took the path through the woods to the
boys’ camp. We hung out with boys. When I got home from camp, I called Ella right
away to make plans with her. I don’t know
why I didn’t call Via. I guess I just didn’t feel like talking about stuff
with her. She would have asked me about my parents, about camp. Ella never really
asked me about things. She was an easier friend to have in that way. She wasn’t
serious like Via. She was fun. She thought it was cool when I dyed my hair pink. She
wanted to hear all about those trips through the woods late at
night school I HARDLY SAW Via at school this year, and when I did it was awkward
I felt like she was judging me. I knew
she didn’t like my new look. I knew she
didn’t like my group of friends. I didn’t much like hers. We never actually argued:
we just drifted away.
Ella and I badmouthed her to each other: She’s such a prude she so this she so
that. We knew we were being mean it was easier to ice her out if we pretended
she had done something to us. The truth
is she hadn’t changed at all: we had. We’d become these other people, and she was
still the person she’d always been. That annoyed me so much and I don't know why.
Once in a while I’d looked to see where she was sitting in the lunchroom, or
check the elective list to see what she’d signed up for. But except for a few
nods in the hallway an occasional “hello,” we never really spoke to each
other. I noticed Justin about halfway through the school year. I hadn’t noticed
him at all before then, other than that he was this skinny CSH dude with thick
glasses and longish hair who carried a violin everywhere. Then one day I saw him
in front of the school with his arm around be
SOA has a boyfriend!” I said to Ella, kind of mocking. I don’t know why it surprised
me that she’d have a boyfriend. Out of the three of us, she was totally the
prettiest: blue, blue eyes and long wavy dark hair. But she just never acted like
she was at all interested in boys. She acted like she was too smart for that
kind of stuff. I had a boyfriend, too: a guy named Zach When I told him I was
choosing the th the elective, he shook his head and said: “Careful you don’t turn
into a drama geek.” Not the most sympathetic dude in the world, but very
cute. Very high up on the totem pole. A varsity jock. I wasn’t planning on taking
theater at first and I saw Via’s name on the signup sheet and just wrote my name
down on the list. I don’t even know why.
We managed to avoid one another throughout most of the semester, like we
didn’t even know each other. Then one day I got to theater class a little early, and
Davenport asked me to run off additional copies of the play he was planning on
having us do for the spring production: The Elephant Man I had heard about it
but I didn’t really know what it was about, so I started skimming through the
pages while I was waiting for the xerox machine. It was about a man who lived
more than a hundred years ago named John Merrick who was terribly
deformed. “We can’t do this play, Mr. D,” I
told him when I got back to class, and I told him why: my little brother has a
birth defect and has a deformed face and this play would hit too close to home. He
seemed annoyed and a little unsympathetic, but I kind of said that my
parents would have a real issue with the school during this play. So anyway, he
ended up switching to ourtown I think I went for the role of Emily Gibbs because
I knew Via was going to go for it, too. It
never occurred to me that I’d beat her for the role
what I miss most ONE OF THE things I miss the most about beia's friendship is
her family. I loved her mom and dad. They were always so welcoming and nice to me.
I knew they loveed their kids more than anything. I always felt safe around them:
safer than anywhere else in the world.
How pathetic that I felt safer in someone else’s house than in my own,
right? And, of course, I loved Auggie. I was never afraid of him: even when I was
little. I had friends that couldn’t believe I’d ever go over to Via’s house
this face creeps me out,” they’d say.
“You’re stupid,” I’d tell them. Auggie’s
face isn’t so bad once you get used to
it. I called Via’s house once just to say hello to Auggie. Maybe part of me was
hoping Via would answer, I don’t know. “Hey, Major Tom!” I said, using my nickname for him.
“Miranda!” He sounded so happy to hear my voice it actually kind of took me by
surprise. “I’m going to a regular school now!” he told me
excitedly. “Really? Wow!” I said, totally shocked. I guess I never really thought
he’d go to a regular school. His parents have always been so protective of him. I
guess I thought he’d always be that little kid in the astronaut helmet I
gave him. Talking to him, I could tell he
had no idea that Via and I weren’t close anymore.
“It’s different in high school,” I explained to him. “You end up hanging out
with loads of different people.” “I have some friends in my new school,” he told me.
“A kid named Jack and a girl named Summer.” “That’s awesome, Auggie,” I said. “Well, I was
just calling to tell you I miss you and I hope you’re having a good year. Feel
free to call me whenever you want, okay, Auggie? You know I love you
always.” “I love you, too, Miranda!” “Say hi to Via for me. Tell her I miss her.”
“I will. Bye!” “Bye extraordinary but no one there to see NEITHER MY MOTHER nor my father
could come see the play on opening night: my mother because she had this thing at
work, and my dad because his new wife was going to have her baby any second now,
and he had to be on call Zach couldn’t come to opening night, either: he had a
volleyball game against Collegiate he couldn’t miss. In fact, he had wanted me
to miss the opening night so I could come cheer him on. My “friends” all went to
the game, of course, because all their boyfriends were playing. Even Ella didn’t
come. Given a choice, she chose the crowd.
So on opening night no one that was remotely close to me was even there. And
the thing is, I realized in my third or fourth rehearsal that I was good at this
ing thing. I felt the part. I understood the words I spoke. I could read the lines
as if they were coming from my brain and my heart. And on opening night, I can
honestly say I knew I was going to be
more than good: I was going to be great. I was going to be
extraordinary, but there would be no one there to see. We were all backstage, nervously
running through our lines and our heads.
I pee threw the curtain at the people taking their seats in the
auditorium. That’s when I saw Auggie walking down the aisle with Isabelle and
Nate. They took three seats in the fifth row, near the middle. Auggie was wearing a
bow tie, looking around excitedly. He had grown up a bit since I’d last seen him,
almost a year ago. His hair was shorter, and he was wearing some kind of hearing
aid now. His face hadn’t changed a bit.
Davenport was running through some last minute changes with the set decoration
I saw Justin pacing off stage left, mumbling his lines
nervously. “Mr. Davenport,” I said, surprising myself as I spoke. “I’m sorry, but I can’t
go on tonight.” Davenport turned around slowly. “What?” he said. “I’m sorry.” “Are you
kidding?” “I’m just I muttered, looking down,
“I don’t feel well sorry. I feel like I’m
going to throw up.” This was a lie. “It’s
just last minute jitters. “No! I can’t do it! I’m telling you.” Davenport looked
furious. “Miranda, this is outrageous.” “I’m sorry!” Davenport took a deep breath, like
he was trying to restrain himself. To be truthful, I thought he looked like he was
going to explode. His forehead turned bright pink. “Miranda, this is absolutely
unacceptable! Now go take a few deep breaths and—” “I’m not going on!” I said
loudly, and the tears came to my eyes fairly easily. “Fine!” he screamed, not looking at
me. Then he turned to a kid named David, who was a set decorator. “Go find Olivia
in the lighting booth! Tell her she’s filling in for Miranda tonight!” “What?” said
David, who wasn’t too swift. “Go!” shouted Davenport in his face. “Now!” The other kids
caught on to what was happening and gathered around. “What’s going on?” said
Justin last minute change of plans,” said Davenport. “Miranda doesn’t feel
well.” “I feel sick,” I said, trying to sound sick. “So why are you still here?” Davenport
said to me angrily. “Stop talking go take off your costume, and give it to Olivia!
Okay? Come on, everybody! Let’s go! Go! Go!” I ran backstage to the dressing room as
quickly as I could and started peeling off my costume 2 seconds later there was
a knock and Via half opened the door.
What is going on?” she said. “Hurry up, put it on,” I answered, handing her the dress.
“You’re sick?” “Yeah! Hurry up!” Via, looking stunned, took off her T-shirt and jeans
and pulled the long dress over her head.
I pulled it down for her, and then zipped up the back. Luckily, Emily web didn’t go
on until 10 minutes into the play, so the girl handling hair and makeup had time
to put Via’s hair up in a twist and do a
quick makeup job. I’d never seen Via with a lot of makeup on: she looked like a
model. “I’m not even sure I’ll remember my lines,” Via said, looking at herself in the
mirror. Your lines.” “You’ll do great,” I said. She looked at me in the mirror. “Why
are you doing this Miss Miranda?” “Olivia!” It was Davenport hus shouting from the
door. “You’re on in 2 minutes. It’s now or
never!” Via followed him out the door, so I never got the chance to answer her
question. I don’t know what I would have said, anyway. I wasn’t sure what the answer
was the performance I WATCHED THE rest of the play from the wings just off stage next
to Davenport. Justin was amazing, and Via, in that heartbreaking last scene, was
awesome. There was one line she fled a bit that Justin covered for her, and no
one in the audience even noticed. I heard Davenport muttering under his breath:
“Good, good, good.” He was more nervous than all of the students put together: the
actors, the set decorators, the lighting team, the guy handling the curtains.
Davenport was a wreck, frankly. The only time I felt any regret, if you even call
it that, was at the end of the play when everyone went out for their curtain
calls. Via and Justin were the last of the actors walking out on stage and the
audience rose to their feet when they took their bows. That, I admit, was a
little bittersweet for me. But just a few minutes later I saw Nate and Isabelle
and Auggie make their way backstage, and they all seemed so
happy. Everyone was congratulating the actors, patting them on the back. It was
that crazy backstage theater mayhem where sweaty actors stand euphoric while
people come worship them for a few seconds. In that crush of people, I
noticed Auggie looking kind of lost. I cut through the crowd as fast as I could
and came up behind him. “Hey!” I said. “Major
Tom after the show I CAN’T SAY why I was
so happy to see August again after so long, or how good it felt when he hugged
me. “I can’t believe how big you’ve gotten,”
I said to him. “I thought you were going
to be in the play!” he said. “I wasn’t up to
it,” I said. “But Via was great, don’t you think?” He nodded. Two seconds later
Isabelle found us. “Miranda!” she said happily, giving me a kiss on the cheek.
And then to August: “Don’t ever disappear like that again.” “You’re the one who
disappeared Augie answered back. “How are you feeling Isabelle said to me. “Via told
us you got sick. “Much better,” I answered.
“Is your mom here?” said Isabelle No, she had work stuff, so it’s
actually not a big deal for me,” I said truthfully. “We have two more shows anyway,
though I don’t think I’ll be as good at
Emily as Via was tonight.” Nate came over and we had basically the same exact
conversation. Then Isabelle said: “Look, we’re going to have a late night dinner
to to celebrate the show. Are you feeling up to joining us? We’d love to have you!”
“Oh, no I started to say please said Auggie. “I should go home,” I said. “We insist,”
said Nate. By now Via and Justin had come over with Justin’s mom, and Via put her
arm around me. “You’re definitely coming,” she said, smiling her old smile at me.
They started leading me out of the crowd, and I have to admit, for the first time
in a very, very long time, I felt absolutely happy thanks for watching please
remember to like And subscribe become a channel member and we'll see you all IN the next video
[Music]